Guide to the African Collection, Yale University Library, Records of the Curator
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
African Collection, Yale University Library, records of the curator
1963-2013
RU 400
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
20.5
The records consist of lists, bibliographies, correspondence, finances and expenses, and publications documenting the activities and operations of the curator of the African Collection at Yale University Library.
Yale University. Library
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-D (YRG 32-D), Records of Yale school and departmental libraries and collections.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
The African Collection contains significant materials on southern Africa and the Anglophone African countries, and French-speaking West and Central Africa. The collection includes books and periodicals and extensive holdings of manuscripts, maps, photographs, and postcards.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of lists, bibliographies, correspondence, finances and expenses, and publications documenting the activities and operations of the curator of the African Collection at Yale University Library.
Academic libraries -- Collection development; Libraries -- Special collections -- Africa; Africa -- Library resources -- United States; Yale University. Library
- Records, circa 1965-1990; Accession 1998-A-127
  Conditions Governing Access
  Accession 1998-A-127 contains university administrative records and is closed until 1 January 2037 by Yale University policy. Contact Public Services for information on requesting access to restricted university records.
  - Champion, 1912–1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Wallerstein Holdings, circa 1954-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Wallerstein Collection-inventory of film, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Wallerstein Collection, title pages, etc, circe 1964-1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Wallerstein Collection, inventory, circa 1954-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Carter-Karis inventory, circa 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Library of Congress Nairobi office, circa 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - D'Souza, John A., circa 1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cape Town University (Rondebosch) II, 1978–1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Mr. W.V. Brelsford - Rhodesia II, 1972–1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - York University-England, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Yale University Library African Collection, 1981–1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Library of Congress III, 1976–1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - South African Institute of Race Relations, 1976–1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Dauphin, miscellaneous letters I, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Dauphin correspondence II, 1964–1968 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Dauphin III, 1968–1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - MAMC Conservation, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - MAMC: Brenner, 1978–1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - MAMCP Brenner, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - MAMC-Dauphin, 1980–1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - MAMC-Hunwick, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - MAMC (NEH), 1974–1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - MAMC-Robinson, 1978–1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - MAMC-Personnel Activity Reporting, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - MAMC-Description, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - MAMC-remss, 1979–1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - MAMC-Davenport standing orders, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - MAMC-financial, 1980–1981 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - MAMC-financial A DWR's travel, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - MAMMP microfilm records and inventory, 1977–1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - MAMMP-DWR's project, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - MAMMP, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Royal Commonwealth Society London, 1977–1983 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Glazier, 1902–1963 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - SARAP-financial file (expenditures), 1977 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - SARAP research in progress, 1975–1977 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - SARAP final report, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Yale Library African Collection report to SARAP etc., 1976 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - SARAP, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - SARAP, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - SARAP, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - SARAP, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - SARAP, 1971–1974 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - SARAP, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - SARAP, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - SARAP research report in progress, 1977–1978 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Carter-Karis, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - SARAP, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Report, circa 1972 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Southern African Research Association, circa 1974 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Archives (SARAP), circa 1970s (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Weisfelder, Richard F., 1971 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Assorted reports, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - SARAP quest, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - SARAP holding, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - SARAP Stringfield, Jessie, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - SARAP newspapers on microfilm, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - SARAP Southern Africa Bibliography list, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Wallerstein correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Titus, Ellen, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - SARAP Questionnaires Chuck, Ambler, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - SARAP Trade Unions and Poli Orgs, circa 1977 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - SARAP Questionnaires positive responses, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Mailing lists for publicity, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Exchange letters-samples, list of recipients, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Templates for form letters, 1976–1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Africana libraries newsletter (Boston University), 1977–1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Association of Research Libraries committee on Africa, 1982–1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Association of Research Libraries committee on Africa, 1979–1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Association of Research Libraries committee on Africa, 1977–1978 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Association of Research Libraries committee on Africa, 1971–1976 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Association of Research Libraries committee on Africa, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Association of Research Libraries committee on Africa, 1964–1970 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Association of Research Libraries committee on Africa, 1963–1964 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - ATLA Board of microtext (Princeton Theological Seminary), 1971–1976 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Aarhus University (Denmark), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Academie des sciences d'outre mer (Paris), 1971 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Academie Royale Brussels, Belgium, 1967–1970 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Addis Ababa University Ethiopia (formerly Haile Selassie University), 1977–1989 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Africa Information Service New York, 1972–1974 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Africa Research Publications Project, 1981–1985 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Africa Research Group Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1969–1972 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Africa Service Institute of New York, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Africa World Press, 1984–1985 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - African Bibliographic Center, Washington, D.C. (D. Matthews), 1963–1985 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Africa Institute of South Africa Pretoria, South Africa, 1968–1988 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - CBD Research Ltd. Beckenham, Kent England, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - CEDAF (Centre D'Etudes et Documentation Africaines, Brussels), 1971–1975 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - CHEAM (Centre de Hautes Etudes Aministratives sur l'Afrique et l'Asie Modernes, Paris), 1967–1977 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - CAMP Committee meeting, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - CAMP Committee, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - CAMP meeting, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - CAMP Committee, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - CAMP Committee meeting, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - CAMP Committee meeting, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - CAMP meeting, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - CAMP committee election, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - CAMP committee, 1980–1981 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - CAMP committee, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - CAMP committee, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - ASA-ACC, 1982–1983 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - CAMP (orders), 1972–1986 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Dauphin, Joanne IV, 1977–1989 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Dellman, Ben-posters, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Durban, 1966–1978 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - East African Academy Research Information Centre, 1963–1973 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Economic History Society of Southern Africa, 1984–1986 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Edinburgh Universitiy library, 1965–1985 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Eduardo Mondlane Universidade, 1980–1988 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Federal Reserve Bank New York, 1968–1970 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Federal University of Technology, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Federation of Women's Institutes (Natal), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Foreign Affairs Association Pretoria, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Foreign and Commonwealth office, 1980–1981 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Foreign Area Materials Center (New York City), 1968–1972 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Foreign Policy Study Association, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Foundation for Education, Science and Technology Pretoria, South Africa, 1976–1988 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Fourah Bay College library (Freetown, Sierra Leone), 1967–1986 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - University of Frankfurt, 1971–1983 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - French Colonial Historical Society, 1975–1983 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Frost and Sullivan, Inc., 1982–1983 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Gambia National Library, 1978–1979 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Garyounis University, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Ghana Institute of Management and Public Administration, Achimota, 1965–1978 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Ghana University Legon & Balme Library, 1978–1979 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Mrs. B. G. Gordon, 1987–1989 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Gosebrink, Jean E. Meeh, 1977–1988 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Guinea Bibliotheque Nationale Conakry, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Guinee, Université de, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Gulbenkian (Gullabi) Foundation, 1964–1978 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Haile Selassie University (Addis), 1965–1976 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Hebrew University of Jerusalem, 1973–1983 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Historical Association of Kenya (c/o History Department) University College Nairobi, 1970–1985 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Historical Association of Zambia, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Historical Society of Port Elizabeth, 1980–1985 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - J. Jeffrey Hoover, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - J Hoover, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Hoover Institution (Stanford) V, 1982–1985 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Hoover Institution (Stanford) IV, 1976–1981 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Human Resources Research Council IV, 1976–1980 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Ibadan exchange, 1966–1967 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Ibadan University, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Kannyo, Edward, 1981–1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - L.S.M. (Liberation Support Movement), 1975–1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Lesotho, National University (Roma), 1982–1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Leyden, University & Afrika Studiecentrum, 1976–1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Library Association, 1967–1977 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Library Journal, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Library of Congress, 1984–1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Library of Congress Photoduplication Office, 1969–1989 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Lincoln University-Pennsylvania, 1981–1982 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - London University Centre of International & Area Studies, 1976–1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Louisville University, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Lourenco Marques Universidade Mozambique, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Universite Lovanium de Kinshasa see: University Nationale du Zaire, Kinshasa campus, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Lutuli Foundation, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Madagascar Bibliotheque Universitaire (Tananarive), 1964–1976 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Maharshi Dayanand University (Centre for Third World Studies & RES), 1987 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - University of Maiduguri, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Makerere University Kampala, Uganda, 1973–1987 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Malawi, University of, 1970–1988 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Marbur/Lahn Universitats-Bibliothek, 1970–1977 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Marquette University, 1975–1987 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Nigerian Field Society, 1964–1985 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Nigerian Institute of International Affairs, Lagos, 1968–1979 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Norsk Utenrikpolitisks Institut, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Northwestern University Library, 1980–1983 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Northwestern University Library IV, 1974–1979 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - OAU: STRC, 1964–1975 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Old Dominion University Norfolk, Virginia, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Omenana, 1983–1984 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - University of the Orange Free State Institute for Contemporary History, 1973–1988 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Research Libraries Group III, 1978–1989 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Rhodes University Library, Grahamstown, South Africa III, 1971–1989 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Rhodes House Library, Oxford, England, 1971–1989 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - South African Library, 1986–1989 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - South African Library IV, 1983–1986 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - South African Library III, 1978–1982 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - South Africa University Library (UNISA) II, 1978–1988 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Tunis Bibliotheque, 1980–1987 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Gandhi-Kallenbach correspondence, 1974–1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - African embassies correspondence, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Algeria, 1967–1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Angola, 1970–1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Belgium, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Belgium Bibliotheque Africaine-M. Geeraerts Ministere des Affaires Etrangeres et du Commerce Exterieu, Belgium, 1971–1977 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Belgium Bibliotheque Royale de Belgique Brussels, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Botswana (Bechuanaland), 1964–1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Botswana National Archives, 1974–1977 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Botswana National Library Service, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Burundi, 1965–1972 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Public Archives of Canada, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Cameroun, 1964–1978 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Canada, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Cape of Good Hope, 1967–1985 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Cape Verde Islands, 1965–1974 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Central African Empire, 1965–1985 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Chad, 1963–1976 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Institut National Tchadien pour les Sciences Humaine, 1973–1974 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - China, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Comores Island, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Congo (Brazza), 1965–1983 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Congo/Zaire (Leopoldville), 1964–1973 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Dahomey, 1964–1971 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Djibouti, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - East African Community Nairobi, Kenya; Arusha, Tanzania, 1963–1973 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Egypt (United Arab Republic), 1963–1972 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Ethiopia, 1965–1989 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - France Embassy archives ORSTOM, 1961–1981 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - France Bibliotheque Nationale, 1965–1967 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Gabon, 1965–1985 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Gambia, 1962–1981 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Ghana, 1970–1981 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Ghana, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Ghana National Archives Tamale, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Great Britain British Information Services New York City, 1963–1968 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Great Britain Foreign & Commonwealth Office London, 1963–1981 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Great Britain Ministry of Overseas Development, 1965–1975 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Guinea, 1960–1974 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Guinea Bissau, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Ireland, 1979–1981 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Italy, 1924 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Ivory Coast, 1963–1974 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Bibliotheque Nationale Abidjan, Ivory Coast, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Kenya, 1970–1988 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Kenya, 1964–1969 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Kenya National Archives, 1977–1984 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Kwazulu Zulu Territorial Authority Nongoma, Natal, 1971–1985 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Lesotho, 1968–1988 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Liberia, 1966–1981 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Liberia, 1972–1980 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Malagasy Rep (Madagascar), 1963–1974 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Malawi (Nyasaland), 1965–1984 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Malawi National Archives, 1971–1975 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Mali, 1964–1981 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Mauritania, 1963–1978 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Mauritius, 1965–1985 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Morocco, 1964–1988 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Bibliotheque, Archives et, 1968–1975 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Mozambique, 1967–1988 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Namibia, 1981–1995 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Namibia II, 1980–1981 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Nigeria State Governments, 1983–1985 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Nigeria, 1965–1987 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Niger, 1965–1977 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - The Netherlands, 1969–1977 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Natal, 1968–1985 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Orange Free State, 1968–1978 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - National Archives of Nigeria, 1964–1975 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Nigeria (Western & Midwestern), 1965–1977 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Nigeria (Northern Region & N.W. State), 1960–1983 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Nigeria (Eastern Region), 1968–1979 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Namibia (South-West Africa), 1968–1978 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Portugal, 1967–1985 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Reunion Island, 1975–1983 (Box 5A, Folder 1)
  - Rwanda, 1963–1986 (Box 5A, Folder 2)
  - St. Helena, 1964–1988 (Box 5A, Folder 3)
  - São Tomé and Príncipe, 1972–1981 (Box 5A, Folder 4)
  - Senegal, 1964–1992 (Box 5A, Folder 5)
  - Senegal Archives, 1969–1976 (Box 5A, Folder 6)
  - Seychelles, 1964–1985 (Box 5A, Folder 7)
  - Sierra Leone, 1965–1985 (Box 5A, Folder 8)
  - Somali Project, 1965–1966 (Box 5A, Folder 9)
  - Somalia, 1963–1986 (Box 5A, Folder 10)
  - African Studies Association III, 1970–1975 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - African Studies Association II, 1964–1969 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - African Studies Association, 1958–1963 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - ASA Association Meeting, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - African Studies Association Waltham, Massachusetts, 1972–1974 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - ASA-ALC Meeting, 1973–1974 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Boston University IV, 1977–1982 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Boston University III, 1972–1976 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Boston University II, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Boston University I, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - California, University at Berkeley I, 1968–1977 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - University of California, Los Angeles I, 1964–1972 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Cambridge University African Studies Centre (CARDAN) I, 1963–1967 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Cape Town University and University Library, 1980–1989 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Cape Town University I, 1965–1977 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - CAMP-Book catalog project, 1970–1972 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Columbia University Libraries (School of International Affairs Library) II, 1976–1977 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Columbia University Libraries (School of International Affairs Library) I, 1971–1975 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Dar Es Salam University College I, 1963–1976 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Ghana University Legon I, 1968–1977 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Hoover Institution III, 1971–1975 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Hoover Institution II, 1969–1970 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Hoover Institution I, 1960–1969 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - HSRC Human Sciences Research Council Raad Vir Geesteswetenskaplike Navorsing I, 1970–1975 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Ibadan University I, 1965–1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Indiana University Bloomington Library II, 1972–1977 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Indiana University Library I, 1964–1971 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs, 1960–1970 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - International African Institute, 1963–1974 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Johannesburg Public Library I, 1966–1976 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Library of Congress Nairobi office, 1985–1990 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Library of Congress II, 1970–1975 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Library of Congress I, 1960–1969 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - SOAS I, 1963–1975 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Makerere University College I, 1966–1972 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Michigan State University Library II, 1970–1978 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Michigan State University I, 1968–1969 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Northwestern University Library III, 1971–1973 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Northwestern University Library II, 1968–1970 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Northwestern University Library I, 1965–1967 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Public Record Office London I, 1966–1976 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Research Libraries Group II, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Research Libraries Group I, 1974–1976 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Rhodes House (Oxford), 1969–1970 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Rhodes University and library (Grahamstown), 1966–1970 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Royal Commonwealth Society, London, 1968–1976 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - South Africa University, Pretoria (UNISA), 1965–1977 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - South African Institute of Race Relations (SAIRR), 1970–1975 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - South African Library, Cape Town, 1976–1977 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - South African Library, 1966–1975 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - State Library, Pretoria, South Africa, 1974–1976 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - State Library, Pretoria, South Africa, 1969–1973 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - State Library, Pretoria, South Africa, 1966–1969 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Swanson, M. William, 1965–1970 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Syracuse University, 1973–1977 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Syracuse University, 1965–1972 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Warsaw University, 1969–1977 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Wisconsin University and Library, 1964–1976 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Witwatersrand University and Library, Johannesburg, 1973–1976 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - South Africa Bantu administration, 1970–1977 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - South Africa: Consul General (New York), 1988–1989 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Yale-Wesleyan South African Research Program (SARP), 1983–1985 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - South Africa Embassy, London, Washington, 1969–1985 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - South Africa Information Department, Pretoria and New York City, 1969–1988 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - South African miscellaneous government departments, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - South Africa miscellaneous, 1984 April (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - South Africa miscellaneous, 1971–1976 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - South Africa miscellaneous, 1977–1984 March (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - South Africa, 1965–1970 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - South African Association for Conflict Intervention (SAACI), 1992–1993 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - South Africa - Bantu and Jans, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - South Africa Bureau for Information, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - South Africa Chamber of Mines, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - South Africa Customs and Excise, 1989–1990 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - South Africa Department of Agricultural Economics and Marketing, 1985–1987 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - South Africa Economic Research and Training Project, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - South Africa Ecumenical Ministry, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - South Africa Foundation, Johannesburg, South Africa, London, Washington, 1975–1986 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - South Africa Government Printing Works, 1995 January–1996 December (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - South Africa Government Printing Works, 1994–1998 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - South Africa Native Economic Commission, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - South Africa State Library, 1989–1995 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - South Africa Parliament and Library, 1966–1987 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - South African Archaeological Society, 1979–1988 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - South African Broadcasting Corporation, 1988–1990 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - South African Council for Scientific and Industrial Research, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - South African and Cape Province local history societies, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Southern Africa Church News, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - South African Communication Service, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - The Consul (information) South African Consulate General, 1991–1996 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - South African Cultural History Museum, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - South African Geographical Society, 1985–1986 (Box 9, Folder 14)